<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tim Whitacre | Notes</title>
    <link>https://timw.co/notes/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tim Whitacre | Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://timw.co/notes/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aaron Draplin - WTF Podcast</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/draplin-wtf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/draplin-wtf/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;#8217;m a huge Aaron Draplin fan (proof), and he was recently featured on the WTF Podcast with Marc Maron. It was on Designer News a week or so ago, but I finally got around to listening to it. Glad I did. Great interview.
Check out the episode here. (NSFW language).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts 2015</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/podcasts-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/podcasts-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About 2 years ago, I took a job at a company which was about 35 minutes from my house. Having such a long commute, I started looking for other things to occupy my time in the car than just music. Enter podcasts. I was hooked right away. Since moving to Atlanta and having a 45 minute to 1.5 hour commute, I love being able to passively learn while driving (or sitting in traffic). As such, I thought I&amp;#8217;d put together a list of the Podcasts that I&amp;#8217;m &lt;em&gt;currenty&lt;/em&gt; enjoying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Go</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/install-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/install-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so I&amp;#8217;ve been playing around with &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; for a while now and have been highly impressed. Recently, when my computer crashed and I was forced to get a new one, I was so busy that I only installed what I needed to get back up and running. This weekend, I had some free time and wanted to play with Go a little more, so I though I&amp;#8217;d share my super simple process of getting it set up. Here we &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=pun+intended&#34;&gt;go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things To Do</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/todo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/todo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a pretty detailed oriented person and try extremely hard to never forget to do something. When a person forgets to do something they said they would, they are not only hurting themselves but many times they are hurting the progress of someone else. I learned this early on in my marriage, and even though I still mess up, I feel like I’ve gotten a lot better at it. I’ve even been able to use the same techniques at my &lt;a href=&#34;http://theironyard.com&#34;&gt;job&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Use Twitter</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First off, I would not consider myself to be a Twitter “power user”, but I do use Twitter a lot. The main reason I use and love twitter is because I treat it as a curated list of great content. It’s curated by people I trust, respect and have actively chosen to keep up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do I actually use this service? I actually get asked this quite often by friends and students. I’ll try and break it down into the simplest form, people I follow and people I add to a list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Fifteen</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/twenty-fifteen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/twenty-fifteen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s 2015 and I’ve not written in over 2 months. Since it’s a new year, my first post hast to be the grossly overdone “resolution” type. So, here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I’m not for resolutions, there are ALWAYS new things I want to do, learn, change and get better at. That said, here are a few things I would like to attempt to do this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Vim</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/vim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you can see from some of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://timw.co/development-tools-updated/&#34;&gt;previous posts&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve been a Sublime Text user for along time now. I started with ST2 and have been using ST3 for about the past year. When I started teaching at &lt;a href=&#34;http://theironyard.com)&#34;&gt;The Iron Yard&lt;/a&gt;. I did this because it is free, open source and a great tool for new developers to use. I still stand by my choice to use this in class and push my students to use it. As a new developer one of the best skills you can learn is version control. Since Atom has tools for git and Github built right in, it helps drive the point home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Platforms</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/blogging-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/blogging-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an instructor at &lt;a href=&#34;http://theironyard.com&#34;&gt;The Iron Yard&lt;/a&gt;, I get asked this question a lot. Here is a VERY simple breakdown of some of my thoughts on different platforms. This is by no means comprehensive, but I feel it gives a pretty solid overview of the platforms I&amp;rsquo;ve had experience with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Learning</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are past the halfway mark for the first Front End class in Atlanta. We are moving fast and everyone is keeping up in an incredible way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/developer-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/developer-resources/</guid>
      <description> Below is a list of ever-changing resources that I use, love and desire to share. Please enjoy responsibly.
General Cheat Sheets  HTML CSS JavaScript jQuery jQuery Pt2 Git  Developers I Personally Follow  John Resig David Walsh Chris Coyier (CSS Tricks) Addy Osmani Douglas Crockford (Book)  Good Reads  Adopting a new Programming Language Revealing the Magic of JavaScript Learn Advanced JavaScript Look at the Big Picture  Other Great Blogs/Sites  General Tech/Design News Daily JS Superhero JS Hack Design JSConf 2014 Videos  List of JavaScript Tools / jQuery Plugins  JavaScript Projects Database of JavaScript Resources List of jQuery Plugins jQuery Plugin Repository  UI Tools  jQuery UI jQuery Mobile Wijmo  Design Resources &amp;amp; Inspirations  Envato Marketplace Creative Market The Noun Project Generate Test Data Faker Library Wes Anderson Color Palette Subtle Background Patterns Dribbble  Show Me The Money  Shopify Stripe Payment API  Great Mac Apps  Alfred  Hosting  Digital Ocean Saddington on Hosting  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Perseverance</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/perseverance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/perseverance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is hard to believe Atlanta’s first Front End Engineering class is now finishing their fourth week. I think back to the dinner we had together the night before class began. Here was a group coming from all over, meeting for the first time and embarking on a twelve week journey. We all came from different backgrounds, states, and skill levels; yet we all shared a common commitment to grow and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining the Iron Yard</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/joining-the-iron-yard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/joining-the-iron-yard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had the privilege over the years to work with some amazing companies and startups and am excited to bring my experiences into the classroom. For me, being able to spend my days building and talking about development is a dream come true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something Crazy</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/something-crazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/something-crazy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to challenge you to do something crazy&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was the first line in an email I received less than 1 month after the startup I was at ran into some trouble. And crazy it is, but also very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Year for Whisk(e)y</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/the-year-for-whiskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/the-year-for-whiskey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve followed me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/timwco&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/timwco&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt; you know that I like to indulge once in a while. So far my drink of choice has been gin. &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/p/jkzy3AJG50/&#34;&gt;Plymouth Gin&lt;/a&gt; to be exact. As great as gin is, I have been told I should be drinking whiskey, at least some of the time. This includes all forms, bourbon, scotch, irish, rye and the likes. I’ll be honest, so far my favorite is rye with scotch being a close second but I have a long list to try and will hopefully be adding to the list as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Many Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/so-many-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/so-many-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t have to tell you this, but there is a lot of stuff on the internet. Obviously most of it is junk, but there is a lot of great content. This begs the question, “how do I consume it all” or rather, “how do I consume as much as I can that is relevant to me so I can keep up to speed in my industry”. This is not an easy task and because content and the way content is presented continually changes, you almost have no choice but to use some sort of service to help you keep up with it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scranton… Meet CoalWork</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/scranton-meet-coalwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/scranton-meet-coalwork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coworking is not a new concept at all. In fact not too long ago while working from home I was doing a ton of research for a coworking spot in this area. Unfortunately there wasn’t one… or at least one that I could be a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Loves : iOS Edition</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/current-loves-ios-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/current-loves-ios-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s finally starting to warm up here in Northeast PA and I’m neck deep in finishing a soon to be released update to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/unmarkit&#34;&gt;Unmark&lt;/a&gt; (formerly nilai.co).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get asked quite often by friends what are the most used apps on my iPhone. I thought this would be a great place to share them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Email</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/thoughts-on-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/thoughts-on-email/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, let me clarify my relationship with email. When it comes the jobs I’ve had, I went from working in an office, to working from home, doing freelance and now back in an office. It might not sound like much of a switch, but each one required different levels of communication to stay up to speed. For instance, my first office job was in a building that had about 150 employees. Not huge, but a lot of people were not close by. When it came to the developers and designers I was currently sharing a project with, we used instant message, but when it came to people in a different division (or people I’d rather not talk to that often) email came in mighty handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year In Review : 2013</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/year-in-review-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/year-in-review-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This time of year, there are thousands of articles (likely more) being written with a similar title or one relating to next years resolutions. I know they are cliched and most people don&amp;rsquo;t really care all that much, but I did write an article at &lt;a href=&#34;http://tim.getbarley.com/2790/doing-more&#34;&gt;the beginning of this year&lt;/a&gt; and wanted to put out a recap of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Loves : Reading Edition</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/current-loves-reading-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/current-loves-reading-edition/</guid>
      <description>While I don&amp;rsquo;t read as many books as I want (or buy), I do spend quite a bit of time reading on a weekly basis. Listed below is a list of what I&amp;rsquo;m currently digging.  Web: The News by Ahmet Sülek &amp;#8211; A mix of Designer News &amp;amp; Hacker News iOS: Interesting by Mike Rundle &amp;#8211; A mix of a ton of great sites&amp;#8230; never be bored again. Web: A List Apart &amp;#8211; Keeps me up on current web trends Web: Indie Vision Music &amp;#8211; A way to stay up to date with my favorite artists Web: Colin Devroe&amp;rsquo;s Blog &amp;#8211; Yeah, he&amp;rsquo;s a friend but he&amp;rsquo;s a good writer and shares some awesome stuff Web: xkcd &amp;#8211; My favorite web comic, smart &amp;amp; witty Web / iOS: Pocket App &amp;#8211; Not specific content, but anything else I find throughout the day, I send here for later Web: Dribbble &amp;#8211; While not much reading here, it&amp;rsquo;s still a great site to keep up with  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Terminal Setup</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/my-terminal-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/my-terminal-setup/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned earlier this year, I switched back to the OS X built in terminal for my everyday coding needs. I like to keep as few programs on my computer as possible and since terminal is baked in, I just stick with it. One thing I missed was some of the customization I got when using programs such as iTerm. To combat that, I began looking around for some ways to trick out my terminal, both in appearance but also (and more importantly) in functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code &amp; Tonic on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/code-tonic-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/code-tonic-on-github/</guid>
      <description>About 2 months ago, I launched a new website &amp;#8211; Code &amp;amp; Tonic. I enjoy blogging but rarely get make time to sit down and do it. So, I had the idea to create a simple website where I could share sites, articles and products that I find awesome but don&amp;rsquo;t want to write an entire article about.
Tonight, I decided to make the code available on GitHub Even though I took an existing awesome WordPress theme and turned it into a Barley theme, I still felt it might help some people who are getting started with Barley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanding My Toolbelt</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/expanding-my-toolbelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/expanding-my-toolbelt/</guid>
      <description>When ever you start a new project it&amp;rsquo;s very important to have the right tools. Today, I decided to tackle one of the many projects that has been looming over my head. Before I got started, I took a step back to figure out which tools I would need.
When doing a project around the house and realizing I need a tool that I currently don&amp;rsquo;t have, it usually means a trip to Lowes and probably a lot of money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love Trello</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/why-i-love-trello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/why-i-love-trello/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m one of those guys who&amp;rsquo;s always writing down ideas for new projects. Generally these are projects that will push a certain skill of mine to the next level. Sometimes, however they are simply something that I just want to do to for fun with no specific agenda.&amp;nbsp;
I was looking for an easy way to organize these &amp;#8220;projects&amp;#8221; and tried about every free version of a project management tool I could find.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barley Helper for Sublime Text</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/barley-helper-for-sublime-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/barley-helper-for-sublime-text/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s no&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;surprise&amp;nbsp;that I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of Sublime Text and in fact most of the team&amp;nbsp;I work with&amp;nbsp;uses it as well. When creating Barley templates, we wanted a way to make it a little easier.&amp;nbsp;
I&amp;rsquo;ve never created a Sublime Text plugin before, but found it to be fairly easy, especially the nature of this one.
Feel free to check it out and let me know your thoughts. If you are a developer looking to create Barley templates, please let us know, and hopefully this will make your life a little easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing on Barley</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/writing-on-barley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/writing-on-barley/</guid>
      <description>I started working for Plain back in May, but had been working on Barley since earlier this year. As with most developers, my website always gets neglected because after working all day long on client&amp;rsquo;s websites, the last thing I want to do at night is work on mine.&amp;nbsp;
Well, I finally had some time this weekend to set up my site on Barley&amp;#8230; it took just a few hours. Going forward it will be much easier for me to continue to write and share my thoughts and possibly some code snippets here and there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate from (dv) to (ve) Server</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/migrate-from-dv-to-ve-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/migrate-from-dv-to-ve-server/</guid>
      <description>Both my company an I have been using Media Temple for years now. We started on their Grid Server (shared hosting) but quickly realized we needed a much better server. That&amp;rsquo;s when we moved to their Dedicated Virtual (dv) server. We&amp;rsquo;ve been running that for the past 3 years and have had no problems at all. In fact it&amp;rsquo;s been the best hosting we&amp;rsquo;ve ever had.
Even though business is going well, we started looking at ways to save a little $$ here and there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Tools - Updated</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/development-tools-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/development-tools-updated/</guid>
      <description>Quite often, I get asked what kind of set up I have and what programs I use on a daily basis. About a year ago, I wrote a post, but below is an updated list&amp;#8230; this time I&amp;rsquo;ll stick to development related programs.
Also, below you&amp;rsquo;ll find some info my current hardware setup as well.
Software
 Coda 2 &amp;#8211; came out in 2012 and I&amp;rsquo;ve been very pleased with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing More</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/doing-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/doing-more/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Twenty years from now you will be more disappointed by the things that you didn&amp;rsquo;t do than by the ones you did do. So throw off the bowlines. Sail away from the safe harbor. Catch the trade winds in your sails. Explore. Dream. Discover.&amp;#8221;
&amp;#8211; Mark Twain
 The above quote is one that my wife tends to use a lot, and for good reason. Honestly, I had never heard it until she brought it to my attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move:DC</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/movedc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/movedc/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend, I had an opportunity to head to Washington DC (first time) with some friends to be part of Move:DC put on by Invisible Children. This event was part of their year long movement to bring Joseph Kony to justice&amp;#8230; also known as Kony 2012.
My wife and I have been supporting IC for the past 4 years and have been very proud to do so. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know, they exist to help bring restitution to those affected by the LRA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guitars &amp; Pedals</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/guitars-pedals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/guitars-pedals/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I thoroughly enjoy music, but many may not know that I also play myself. I have the privilege of co-leading the student band at our church on a weekly basis and getting to lead a group of up to 75 middle school students in worship every Sunday.
Another thing about me is I&amp;rsquo;m a gear hound&amp;#8230; I can never seem to have enough. While I consider myself very good with our finances, I do have a week spot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Produce Brands</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/produce-brands/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/produce-brands/</guid>
      <description>Life tends to stay pretty hectic&amp;#8230;. and I rarely have time to pick up new projects. However, when a good friend approached me with a new idea a month or so back, I knew I would be a fool not to go for it.
I won&amp;rsquo;t go into too much detail as of yet&amp;#8230; but basically I&amp;rsquo;ll say this:
EVERYONE eats produce&amp;#8230; from one place or another and with all the new technology out there, the produce game is changing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Fun</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/summer-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/summer-fun/</guid>
      <description>This summer I had the awesome opportunity to go on a trip with a group of students from our church. The trip is called iPac and last for two weeks. The first part of the trip was a serving part, where the students helped build a home for Habitat for Humanity of Greater Birmingham. The second week was spent at a camp in Panama City Beach, Florida called BigStuf.
I had the privilege to join the students for the second week (yes I know&amp;#8230; the easy part), but it was still well worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress - Get Rounded # of Posts</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/wordpress-get-rounded-of-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/wordpress-get-rounded-of-posts/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;ve written about this before, but decided to post it up here for your (and my) sake as a reference.
&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;
I had a client who had a massive amount of articles on his website and by using a content aggregation (a Google nightmare), he was adding more and more by the minute. Because of the vast number of articles, he wanted a way to show his visitors the size of his site but wanted it to look a little prettier than just counting all posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Design Question</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/responsive-design-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/responsive-design-question/</guid>
      <description>First off&amp;#8230;. if you are unfamiliar with the term &amp;#8220;responsive web design&amp;#8221; (RWD) check out A List Apart&amp;rsquo;s article on responsive web design.
Now that that&amp;rsquo;s out of the way. I&amp;rsquo;d like to take a look at a recent issue brought up by a client I was working with. In building out their website with fluid grids and RWD, we came across a small issue. That issue was that when a visitor of the website was using a tablet, phone or any smaller-dimension browsing device, there was no way for them to get back to a full site view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reboot</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/reboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/reboot/</guid>
      <description>So, it&amp;rsquo;s that time again. It comes once a year or so. The time to reformat your hard drive and get your computer as clean as a whistle.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but over time I download and install many different apps and then uninstall just about as many. That leaves my computer hating me. I can sense it getting more and more frustrated every time I drag a new application into the folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckDuckGo - just works!</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/duckduckgo-just-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/duckduckgo-just-works/</guid>
      <description>Aiming to be a competitor of Google, so far they are doing a fairly good job. I mean let&amp;rsquo;s face it, they&amp;rsquo;ll never be as big as the company but they are fast and show very relevant results.
I really enjoy the fact that they don&amp;rsquo;t lock you into the bubble, which means that you get results based on your search, not based on what you&amp;rsquo;ve liked, searched for prior or what THEY (Google, Bing, Yahoo) think you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Noise Lounge</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/introducing-the-noise-lounge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/introducing-the-noise-lounge/</guid>
      <description>So, now that I&amp;rsquo;m done ranting about Godaddy and all of the nonsense going on over there, I decided to focus my efforts on something more positive. Over the holiday break (I took a few days off), I decided to put the finishing touch on a website I&amp;rsquo;d been wanting to launch for some time.
A few months back, I reached out to some friends who share a similar interest in music but were not completely satisfied with the current sites out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Go Daddy!</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/goodbye-go-daddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/goodbye-go-daddy/</guid>
      <description>Ohhhh man, I can&amp;rsquo;t even begin to explain how happy I am right now. Let me give you a little back story&amp;#8230;
&amp;nbsp;
Quite a few years ago when I first started getting into the &amp;#8220;web business&amp;#8221; I needed a registrar. Back then there wasn&amp;rsquo;t too many to choose from and everywhere I looked Go Daddy stood out as not only being the cheapest but being the biggest and most reliable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piling up</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/piling-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/piling-up/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again&amp;#8230; Thanksgiving is over, Black Friday and Cyber Monday have passed. It&amp;rsquo;s now time to look forward to Christmas. Christmas shopping is underway, I finally let my wife to play Christmas music and decorate the house. The one thing that glares at me though, is that just a week beyond Christmas is New Years&amp;#8230; and the start of 2012. I&amp;rsquo;m not big on resolutions or anything of that nature, but I am big on starting fresh and I&amp;rsquo;ve got a TON of projects sitting around that I&amp;rsquo;d really like to get done and completed before the end of this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thankful</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/thankful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/thankful/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve safely made it to Kansas and am going to be spending the next week with most of my immediate family. There are 11 of us in the house plus 4 dogs. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be a great week!
I was sitting around this afternoon just thinking of how lucky I am. Not be cause of what I have, but because I am part of a big family that truly loves each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Stuff is Fun</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/free-stuff-is-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/free-stuff-is-fun/</guid>
      <description>Everyone loves free stuff&amp;#8230; and that&amp;rsquo;s why myself and the others involved in the application Hosted Notes have decided to make it free. That&amp;rsquo;s right.. free. Now go signup and enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Post Tags or Categories</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/wordpress-post-tags-or-categories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/wordpress-post-tags-or-categories/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m in active development in a new WordPress theme and came across the age old question. Should I built in support for tags or not? Should I just leave the user with the ability to only use categories? I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to give them the option, but would I be doing them an injustice since most people rarely use tags and the ones that do, don&amp;rsquo;t use them right?
I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of TentBlogger and decided to check out his website for an opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oldie but a Goodie</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/oldie-but-a-goodie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/oldie-but-a-goodie/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s an old video I made a over a year ago for fun. Feel free to check it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Human Mind</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/the-human-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/the-human-mind/</guid>
      <description>So yesterday I was thinking it was time to clean up my computer a little bit as I felt it was running a little sluggish. I looked around and finally found a program called &amp;#8220;Mac Keeper&amp;#8221; and thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a try. I should have done my research first as it ended up deleting quite a few of things I needed, such as a ton of program settings. Now I&amp;rsquo;m sure there&amp;rsquo;s a setting that would avoid this but either way it happened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Addition</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/new-addition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/new-addition/</guid>
      <description>So it&amp;rsquo;s been a bit since I&amp;rsquo;ve added anything to my pedal board (which I will review at some point), but I was recently given a gift from a client. It&amp;rsquo;s an Ernie Ball Volume Pedal JR. I&amp;rsquo;ve never used a VP before but have always been interested in getting one. The pedal came in the mail yesterday as a thank you for a recent site I built (which we&amp;rsquo;ll keep nameless at this point) and I&amp;rsquo;ve only gotten to play with it a little bit last night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site vs App</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/site-vs-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/site-vs-app/</guid>
      <description>When working on proposals for new work, I often get a raised eyebrow when someone hears that a simple app can cost a lot more than a large website. They think because the app might only consist of a single page and the site hundreds that the site is somehow much harder to put together.
When pondering this, I came up with an analogy&amp;#8230; condos vs cottages. A condo can house many families while a cottage is generally for a single small family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS 5 - My Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/ios-5-my-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/ios-5-my-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Well, I updated to iOS 5.0 just a couple days ago and so far so good. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe that an OS update of any kind can show considerable improvement in speed when the device hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed at all&amp;#8230; as I&amp;rsquo;m still running the iPhone 4.
I&amp;rsquo;m very impressed with the updates to the notifications and the camera as a whole but to me the one thing that I love the most is the text-expansion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from Vacation</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/back-from-vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/back-from-vacation/</guid>
      <description>Just got back from vacation and it was wonderful. I absolutely love what I do, but even those of us who have our &amp;#8220;dream jobs&amp;#8221; need a vacation from it every once in a while.

My wife and I were able to spend the last week at a cabin on Lake Anna in the middle of Virginia. We planned our trip perfectly so there was very few people on the lake while we were there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purple Door - Mobile App</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/purple-door-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/purple-door-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>So getting ready to leave for Purple Door Festival 2011 tomorrow and in the meantime I thought I&amp;rsquo;d throw together a quick mobile app using jQuery Mobile so I&amp;rsquo;d have a better way of keeping the schedule in my pocket.
Anyone interested can find it here &amp;#8211; Purple Door Mobile Schedule</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Hour Fast 2011</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/30-hour-fast-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/30-hour-fast-2011/</guid>
      <description>I consider myself luck that over the past 3 years I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to be a part of Parker Hill and their student ministries department. Over this last weekend I was able to take part in what is called the 30 hour fast. Basically all of the students from middle school to high school raise money and awareness by giving up their right to eat for 30 hours.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a clip of the highlight video:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosted Notes Launch</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/hosted-notes-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/hosted-notes-launch/</guid>
      <description>I should probably be more worried about what I&amp;rsquo;m going to get my wife today, but I also wanted to take time out to announce the launch of the first ever online web app that I was able to be a part of.
It&amp;rsquo;s called Hosted Notes and it&amp;rsquo;s tool to help keep track of passwords. It was originally concieved with freelances in mind. When doing a website for a client, you usually end up with many different passwords and programs you need access to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argyll Studios Re-Design</title>
      <link>https://timw.co/notes/argyll-studios-re-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timw.co/notes/argyll-studios-re-design/</guid>
      <description>After many months of working on this site, we&amp;rsquo;re finally ready to make our launch public to the world.
Presenting the redesign of my company &amp;#8211; Argyll Studios</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>