<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Media on Tim Whitacre | Notes</title>
    <link>http://timw.co/categories/social-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Media on Tim Whitacre | Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://timw.co/categories/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Use Twitter</title>
      <link>http://timw.co/post/twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://timw.co/post/twitter/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;First off, I would not consider myself to be a Twitter “power user”, but I do use Twitter a lot. The main reason I use and love twitter is because I treat it as a curated list of great content. It’s curated by people I trust, respect and have actively chosen to keep up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do I actually use this service? I actually get asked this quite often by friends and students. I’ll try and break it down into the simplest form, people I follow and people I add to a list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;following-on-twitter&#34;&gt;Following on Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, I’m currently following less than 150 people. The people who are on this list fall into one of the following categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Family Members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal Friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close Co-Workers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies or Organizations I respect or own&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t fall into one of these categories, then you don’t get a follow. Please don’t take it personally. I probably really like you and think you have a lot of great things to say, but you are not quite “follow” status in my book. Instead, you will most likely land yourself on one of my Twitter lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lists-on-twitter&#34;&gt;Lists on Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a handful of lists on Twitter. Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atlantians &amp;#8211; Interesting people or places in Atlanta, GA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scrantonians &amp;#8211; Interesting people or places in Scranton, PA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Techies &amp;#8211; Developers, Teachers, Designers &amp;#8211; all things tech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good Work &amp;#8211; Pastors, Churches, Organizations &amp;#8211; only ones I support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Iron Yard &amp;#8211; Everyone I work with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Iron Yard : Students &amp;#8211; People who have been gone to TIY&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That about sums it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice, I don’t have a &lt;em&gt;Comedians&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Celebrities&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Athletes&lt;/em&gt; category. This is mainly because I try to limit myself from going down crazy rabbit holes on the internet. Also, by only tracking people that actively have a part of my life it helps keep the content relevant to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter is a great resource, just make sure you find the way to use it that makes sense for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>